NYSUT Mid-Hudson Regional Office Files. 6174/011
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Program Cabinet, 1990 (Box 20, Folder 35)
  Notebook of printed and handwritten notes of Program Cabinet meetings and student discipline issues
- Rhinecliff District Financial Statements, 1998 (Box 20, Folder 36)
  Rhinecliff Union Free School District Financial Statements and Supplemental Information, June 30, 1998
- Rhinecliff District Financial Statements, 1999 (Box 20, Folder 37)
  Rhinecliff Union Free School District Financial Statements and Supplemental Information, June 30, 1999
- RTA, 1998-1999 (Box 20, Folder 38)
  Billing statements; checking account statements; school district voluntary deduction reports; NYSUT dues transmittal (local membership) reports
- RTA, 1997-1998 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  NYSUT dues reports (spreadsheets); cancelled checks on Rhinecliff Teachers Association account; checking account statements; expense receipts; bills and copies of checks to American Arbitration Association
- RTA, 1996-1997 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  NYSUT dues reports (spreadsheets); checking account statements; expense receipts
- RTA Treasury, 1995-1996 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  Handwritten RTA budget for 1996-97; check duplicates; AFT Action newsletters re education funding, vouchers, federal appropriations, and other issues; NYSUT local membership reports; checking account statements
- Rhinecliff District Budget Reports, 2000 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  Rhinecliff Union Free School District line-item budget reports
- RTA Checks, 2000 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  New checkbooks
- RTA Treasury, 1994-1995 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  Checking statements; NYSUT and Subsidiary Consolidated Schedule of Expenses and Allocation between Chargeable and Nonchargeable Expenses for the year ended August 31, 1994; American Federation of Teachers, AFL-CIO, Combined Statement of General Fund, Militancy Fund, and Defense Fund Expenses and Allocation between Chargeable Expenses and Nonchargeable Expenses for the year ended April 30, 1994; NYSUT Local Membership Reports; Rhinecliff Union Free School District printout of teacher dues deductions; AFT Action newsletters
- RTA Treasury, 1993-1994 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  Checking statements; NYSUT Local Membership Reports; Rhinecliff Union Free School District printout of teacher dues deductions; AFT Action newsletters
- RTA Treasury, 1992-1993 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  Checking statements; NYSUT Local Membership Reports; Rhinecliff Union Free School District printout of teacher dues deductions; duplicate checks
- RTA Treasury, 1992-1993 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  Checking statements; NYSUT Local Membership Reports; Rhinecliff Union Free School District printout of teacher dues deductions; miscellaneous receipts
- NYSUT, 1994-1995 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  Payroll deduction authorization cards; NYSUT local membership reports; NYSUT publication, "Membership reporting and dues transmittal 94-95"
- RTA Treasury Information, 1992 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  Bank statements; dues structure for 1992-93; Rhinecliff district printout of dues deductions; miscellaneous receipts
- Vote Cope, 1995 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  VOTE/COPE (Committee on Political Education) 1995 instruction manual; posters; donation cards
- NYSUT, 1993 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  NYSUT Local Membership Reports (list of dues collected per member); memo to local presidents from NYSUT treasurer Fred Nauman re financial controls; cover letter to local officials for membership kit
- NYSUT Membership, 1991-1992 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  NYSUT booklet, "Membership reporting and dues transmittal 91-92"; payroll deduction authorization cards; cover letter to local officials for membership kit; dues/agency fee transmittal report
- NYSUT Membership, 1999 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  NYSUT booklet, "Membership reporting and dues transmittal handbook," 1999-2000; payroll deduction authorization cards; membership kit cover letter
- NYSUT Membership, 1995-1996 (Box 21, Folder 16)
  NYSUT booklet, "Membership reporting and dues transmittal handbook," 1995-96; payroll deduction authorization cards
- Financial Statements-RUFSD, 1979 (Box 21, Folder 17)
  Rhinecliff Union Free School District Financial Statements, June 30, 1979
- Rhinebeck Savings Bank, 1989 (Box 21, Folder 18)
  Blank check books for Rhinecliff Teachers Association; duplicate checks (copies)
- RTA Financial, 2000 (Box 21, Folder 19)
  Rhinecliff Union Free School District Comprehensive Budget Status Summary for various funds (printout)
- WCT-Sub Pay, 1993-1994 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  Wappingers Congress of Teachers materials on teacher's employment history, full-time probationary appointment, change to part-time
- WCT-Illness, 1994 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  Correspondence re medical leave, including doctor's notes
- WCT-Tenure, 1993-1994 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  Correspondence re tenure status of library media specialist whose job might be eliminated
- WCT-Special Ed. Review, 1993-1994 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  Wappingers Central School District Process for the Committee on Special Education; memo noting Wappingers Congress of Teachers' request for review of procedure
- WCT-Termination, 1993-1994 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  Work performance memorandum for special education teacher; draft letters of resignation
- WCT-Legal Review T.D.O./BOE, 1993 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  Request for legal review to NYSUT legal counsel re possible conflict of interest by Board of Education in designating an official newspaper owned by the head of an anti-tax organization (Taxpayer Defense Organization) who funded winning candidates for school board; request by Wappingers Congress of Teachers to NYSUT field rep for more information about the anti-tax group and its funding sources
- WCT-2510 Litigation, 1991-1992 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  Correspondence and legal briefs in Delesso-Neubauer et al. v. Board of Education for the Wappingers Central School District et al. re rights of excessed teachers
- WCT-Inclusion Teacher, 1991 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  Handwritten log re student, written by inclusion teacher, supplied to president of Wappingers Congress of Teachers
- WCT-OSHA, 1994 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  Statement re air quality in classroom and its affect on health; report on indoor air quality at Oak Grove School; related correspondence
- WCT-Disciplinary Letters, 1994-1995 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  Correspondence from superintendent, president of Wappingers Congress of Teachers, and others re foreign language teacher, who refused to sign disciplinary letters, avail herself of representation by the union, or otherwise respond to 3020-a charges; letter of dismissal
- WCT-Federal Suit Retroactive Raises, 1995 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  Legal briefs
- WCT-Medical Leave Without Pay, 1976-1991 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  Correspondence re medical leave without pay for teacher, 1976-80; correspondence re retirement credit, 1991; unrelated correspondence re grievances, 1991
- WCT-Sick Days, 1994-1995 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  Correspondence re sick days
- WCT-Racism, 1993-1994 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  Statements by teacher re allegations of racism for casual remarks to student that included a reference to his race; letter of suspension; 3020-a hearing charges including misconduct and incompetence; panel decision acquitting teacher of charges
- WCT-IPC, 1993-1994 (Box 22, Folder 15)
  Public Employment Relations Board decision and order in Wappingers Central School District (charging party) and Wappingers Congress of Teachers/NYSUT/AFT (respondent) re WCT failure to negotiate in good faith by publishing a cartoon in the WTC Commentator newsletter critical of Board of Education; Improper Practice Charge by district re cartoon; related materials, including reference to student newspaper faculty advisor, brought up on 3020-a disciplinary charges
- WCT Inclusion Planning Time, 1993-1994 (Box 22, Folder 16)
  Demand for negotiation of change in working conditions (inclusion program); related memo from WCT president to NYSUT labor relations specialist/field representative Fran Wolf
- WCT-Legal Review-Confidential Student Assistant Counsel, 1993 (Box 22, Folder 17)
  Legal opinion of attorney for Wappingers school district re confidentiality of student information under FERPA, obligation or prohibition of certain school employees to inform parents of students under age 18 of pregnancy and/or intent to obtain an abortion; request to NYSUT by WCT for legal review
- WCT-Legal Reviews, 1995-1996 (Box 22, Folder 18)
  Requests for NYSUT legal reviews of various issues by Wappingers Congress of Teachers; complaint from NYSUT labor relations specialist Fran Wolf to NYSUT Mid-Hudson Regional Director Jan Conti that WCT president Ron Warman was requesting too many legal reviews; information about district counsel Victor Yannacone
- WCT-District Meeting, 1995 (Box 22, Folder 19)
  11/7. Letter from NYSUT labor relations specialist Fran Wolf to Wappingers district superintendent and attorney re outstanding issues re occupational therapist, physical therapist, and assistant positions; handwritten notes
- WCT-Retirement, 1994 (Box 22, Folder 20)
  Correspondence between WCT president and retired teacher re possible health insurance benefits
- WCT-Insubordination, 1993-1994 (Box 22, Folder 21)
  Materials re 3020-a hearing (insubordination) against faculty advisor for student newspaper that attempted to print a cartoon critical of the school board; appeal by district to Commissioner of Education (dismissed); column in local newspaper re controversy
- WCT-Agency Fee Refund Procedure District Issue, 1993-1994 (Box 22, Folder 22)
  Correspondence between WCT president, district personnel officer, and NYSUT re dues deduction
- WCT-Attendance/Punctuality Policy, 1993-1994 (Box 22, Folder 23)
  Draft and adopted district policies and related correspondence
- WCT-Sexual Harassment, 1993-1994 (Box 22, Folder 24)
  Performance evaluation re guidance counselor re allegation of sexual harassment; related disciplinary memos
- WCT-Sexual Harassment, 1993 (Box 22, Folder 25)
  Legal documents dismissing case against guidance counselor by parents of student; invoice by attorney; correspondence re reimbursement by NYSUT legal defense fund
- WCT-Commentator Cartoon, 1993 (Box 22, Folder 26)
  Wappingers Congress of Teachers newsletter, the WCT Commentator, including cartoon, originally published in student newspaper and confiscated by administration, critical of school board, June 25, 1993; student newspaper, the Tomahawk, with offending cartoon, June 1993; memo from WCT president to NYSUT field representative Fran Wolf, re warning that district might bring Improper Practice Change against the union
- WCT-Sexual Abuse, 1993-1994 (Box 22, Folder 27)
  Materials related to lawsuit against school psychologist by parents of student claiming sexual abuse
- WCT-Reduction in Activities, 1993-1994 (Box 22, Folder 28)
  Grievance re district-wide reduction in activities and assignments
- WCT-Tenure, 1972-1996 (Box 22, Folder 29)
  Correspondence re tenure; request for legal review, with details of assignments; probationary appointment notice, 1972; handwritten notes re history of teaching, permanent certifications
- WCT-Retirement OWBPA, 1995-1996 (Box 22, Folder 30)
  Materials re retirement incentive issue
- WCT-Negotiations General Info., 1995-1996 (Box 22, Folder 31)
  Form with questions for bargaining issues
- WCT-Miscellaneous (not pending), 1994-1996 (Box 22, Folder 32)
  Letter from Wappingers Congress of Teachers president Ron Warman to NYSUT officials, complaining of lack of cooperation in obtaining requested legal reviews of issues, October 24, 1995; related correspondence from Warman to NYSUT president Tom Hobart; correspondence re requested reimbursement from NYSUT legal defense fund for WCT member; correspondence re payment schedule for teaching special education students, 1995-96; list of WCT executive board; retainer agreement for Ray Kruse, attorney for the district; letter from Kruse announcing he was no longer representing the district, informing NYSUT that Victor Yannacone was new attorney, August 1, 1995
- WCT-Intolerable Behavior, 1987-1991 (Box 22, Folder 33)
  Description of 3020-a charges (immoral character, insubordination, conduct unbecoming of a teacher); performance evaluation/disciplinary letter re "intolerable" behavior, June 18, 1991; counseling memo, September 4, 1990
- WCT-Substitutes, 1993 (Box 22, Folder 34)
  Draft settlement of grievance, "insufficient substitutes"; cover memo to NYSUT field rep Fran Wolf, August 18, 1993
- WFW Overtime, 1989-1993 (Box 22, Folder 35)
  Memos re grievances re overtime for maintenance workers
- WFW-Courier Workday, 1984 (Box 22, Folder 36)
  Agreement re school courier/custodial worker vacancy, with outline of job duties
- WFW-Pay Schedule, 1993 (Box 22, Folder 37)
  Memos re pay schedule for ten-month employees
- WFW-Epinephrine Injections, 1993 (Box 22, Folder 38)
  Draft procedures for administering injections in an emergency when school nurses were not available, October 15, 1993; information re bee sting allergy; notes about students with bee sting allergies; instruction from school physician in cases of emergency; correspondence between NYSUT labor relations specialist Steve Berman and district re instruction for bus monitors
- WFW-Vacation Schedules, 1992 (Box 22, Folder 39)
  Vacation schedules for groundskeepers, 1992-93; time sheets; vacation request forms; grievance re groundskeeper re unreasonable denial of vacation day, September 9, 1992; handwritten notes
- WFW-Just Cause/Discipline, 1993 (Box 22, Folder 40)
  Grievance for disparate treatment for inappropriate (revealing) dress on behalf of driver/cleaner and others similarly situated, May 20, 1993; settlement, January 13, 1994; handwritten notes; disciplinary letter re bus accident, June 9, 1993; employee warning report re dirty floor, March 12, 1992; third notice re violation of punch in/ punch out policy, January 31, 1991
- WFW-Respirators, 1997 (Box 22, Folder 41)
  Letter from Wappingers Federation of Transit Custodial and Maintenance Workers to superintendent demanding district withdraw new requirement that employees take a "respirator fit test"
- WFW-Floating Custodial Workers, 1987-1988 (Box 22, Folder 42)
  Job description for custodian, revised August 1, 1975, revised March 20, 1979; job postings for night custodians, September 1987; list of custodians, with hire dates; grievance re floating custodial positions, August 18, 1987; notice of hearing, October 8, 1987; job descriptions for senior groundskeeper, bus driver, and head maintenance mechanic positions, September 1986; arbitration brief; handwritten notes; related correspondence
- WFW-Just Cause/Discipline, 1993-1994 (Box 22, Folder 43)
  Grievance and related correspondence re suspension of bus driver for speeding
- WFW-Doctor's Certificate, 1993 (Box 22, Folder 44)
  6/1. Grievance and related correspondence over docking bus driver for hours missed until she could produce a doctor's note; memo re unsatisfactory record of attendance; positive drug test results; note from doctor documenting prescription for pain for arthritis in arm
- WFW-Activity Driver's Pay, 1993 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  Wappingers Federation of Workers grievance re work day, work week, and wages (overtime) for activity (bus) drivers
- WFW-Discipline, 1993 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  Statement re random urine test incident, Fishkill Plains Elementary
- WFW-Bus Driver Discipline, 1993-1994 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  Disciplinary letter to bus driver re suspension following conviction for Driving While Ability Impaired
- WFW-Dr. Note, 1993 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  Grievance re disparate treatment requiring doctor's note for sick leave
- WFW-Class Action Past Practice, 1993 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  Grievance re smoking by bus driver
- WFW-Just Cause/Discipline, 1993 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  Grievance re suspension for speeding by bus driver
- WFW-Discipline, 1994 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  Grievance re suspension without pay for courier; letter noting settlement
- WFW-Attendance and Leave Policy, 1994 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  Grievance re attendance and leave policy
- WFW-Booth v. Leggerio Const., 1995 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  Subpoena and related correspondence re Booth v. Leggerio Construction and Leggerio Construction v. All County Security
- WFW-Discipline, 1997 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  Disciplinary memo to bus driver for negligence and insubordination; grievance re lack of just cause
- WFW-Attendance Policy, 1993 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  Memo from district re new attendance policy
- WFW-Grievances, 1988 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  Opinion and award in arbitration between Wappingers school district and Wappingers Federation of Transit, Custodial and Maintenance Workers re grievance; grievance re driver directed by district to resign from driver position to become custodian floater (nights); union post-hearing brief in arbitration; district post-hearing memorandum; related correspondence
- WFW-RCK Harassment, 1995 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  Wappingers district sexual harassment policy; complaint form; handwritten notes
- Roscoe-Preferring Disciplinary Charges, 1997 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  Stipulation of Settlement in Lieu of Preferring Disciplinary Charges re teacher; letter of resignation
- WFW-Board Elections, 1997 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  Letter from NYSUT Mid-Hudson Regional office re help with Wappingers school board election and budget vote, February 18, 1997; related materials
- WFEA, 1993 (Box 23, Folder 16)
  Collective Bargaining Agreements between district and Wappingers Federation of Educational Assistants (Monitors), July 1, 1991 through June 30, 1993, and July 1, 1988 through June 30, 1991; Memorandum of Agreement through year 1997-98; salary schedule; handwritten notes; draft contract proposals; description of school monitors
- WFW-Duty of Fair Representation, 1996 (Box 23, Folder 17)
  Answer by Wappingers Federation of Transit, Custodial and Maintenance Workers to Improper Practice charge to PERB re failure of duty of fair representation; posting for vacancy for bus driver (cleaner); letter withdrawing complaint
- WFW-Discipline, 1995-1996 (Box 23, Folder 18)
  Grievance on behalf of spare driver re suspension without just cause, February 6, 1996; incident report; disciplinary letter to Jennings from district for negligence in failure to drop off students at correct stops; personnel records; district's post-hearing brief in arbitration; opinion and award by arbitrator; handwritten notes
- WFW-Superintendent's Tentative Budget, 1995-1997 (Box 23, Folder 19)
  Wappingers Central School District Superintendent's Tentative Budget, 1996-97; Superintendent's Recommended Budget, 1995-96
- WFW/WCT Article 78, 1996 (Box 23, Folder 20)
  Brief of civil action challenging Wappingers district's retaining of Education Alternatives, Inc., as financial consultants
- WFW-Worker's Comp, 1995 (Box 23, Folder 21)
  Request from Wappingers Board of Education for bargaining units to send representatives to discuss processing of workers' compensation claims
- WFW-Health Insurance Buyout, 1996 (Box 23, Folder 22)
  Arbitration opinion and award re health insurance buyout for bus driver who married another employee, cancelled her health insurance, and enrolled in her husband's; handwritten notes
- WFW-Termination, 1996 (Box 23, Folder 23)
  Grievance re termination of custodian for failing drug test; related correspondence
- Wappingers Cafeteria Workers, 1994 (Box 23, Folder 24)
  Salary agreement, 1990, and side letter of agreement, 1991; warning letter to cafeteria worker re argument with substitute worker, 1994
- WFW-Time Card, 1993-1994 (Box 23, Folder 25)
  Memorandum of Intent between Wappingers Central School District and Wappingers Federation of Workers re successor agreement commencing July 1, 1989; Memorandum of Agreement, June 18, 1990; opinion and award in arbitration of grievance re time clocks, 1994; Wappingers Federation of Workers newsletters, September and October 1992; time card procedure; revised time card procedure, September 14, 1992; grievance re time clocks; handwritten notes
- WFW Subcontracting, 1993 (Box 23, Folder 26)
  Grievance re subcontracting of electrical work on behalf of two maintenance mechanics; related correspondence; handwritten notes
- WFEA Suspension and Termination, 1994 (Box 23, Folder 27)
  Incident reports; personnel records of school bus monitor John Esposito, including letters of suspension and termination; handwritten notes; Freedom of Information requests
- WFW-Custodial Seniority, 1994 (Box 23, Folder 28)
  Grievance re custodian; post-hearing brief on behalf of the association (Wappingers Federation of Transit, Custodial and Maintenance Workers) in arbitration with district; opinion and award in arbitration; non-layoff seniority list by department; handwritten notes
- WFW-Sick Bank, 1993 (Box 23, Folder 29)
  Handwritten list of Workers Compensation cases 1992-1993; other handwritten notes; memo re status of sick bank, noting negative effect of Workers Comp cases
- WFW-Subcontracting Night Watchman, 1993 (Box 23, Folder 30)
  Grievance re subcontracting; related correspondence
- WFW-Recall, 1993 (Box 23, Folder 31)
  Grievance for excessed (laid off) maintenance mechanic, who was not called back when vacancy occurred; job posting; correspondence showing attempts by district to contact Todaro re vacancy; related correspondence
- WFEA Constitution Contract, 1985-1988 (Box 23, Folder 32)
  Collective Bargaining Agreement by and between Wappingers Central School District and Wappingers Federation of Educational Assistants, July 1, 1985 to June 30, 1988; Constitution for Wappingers Federation of Educational Assistants (based on constitution for Educational Service Employees Federation), 1985
- WFEA Contract, 1989 (Box 23, Folder 33)
  Job description for monitors; correspondence requesting increases in salary for monitors performing similar work as teacher substitutes
- WFEA-Payroll Deduction, 1985-1986 (Box 23, Folder 34)
  Copies of payroll deduction authorization cards; list of staff not turning in authorization cards or enrollment form
- NYSUT Membership Request, 1985 (Box 23, Folder 35)
  Letter to NYSUT president Tom Hobart from president of Wappingers Congress of Teachers, authorizing school monitors to form a secondary local in the district, Wappingers Federation of Educational Assistants, to be affiliated with NYSUT, March 28, 1985; list of officers; Constitution; request to district superintendent by NYSUT field representative Harry Fairbanks to negotiate with monitors as Wappingers Federation of Educational Assistants
- Aides-Monitors, 1991 (Box 23, Folder 36)
  Response by district to negotiating points with school monitors, June 19, 1991
- Workshops-Summer Leadership Conference, 1988 (Box 23, Folder 37)
  Outline of agenda for 1988 Summer Leadership Conference for School Related Personnel; instructional materials re organization and operation, creating an image, organizing your local, membership, enforcing the contract
- WFEA-Building Rep Workshop, 1986 (Box 23, Folder 38)
  Sept. Tabbed sections on contract, constitution, officers, and membership
- Wap. WFEA, 1991 (Box 23, Folder 39)
  Draft of collective bargaining agreement by and between Wappingers Central School District and Wappingers Federation of Educational Assistants (Monitors), July 1, 1991 through June 30, 1993; list of modifications proposed by district; draft WFEA proposals; list of school monitors with hourly rates; related correspondence; handwritten notes
- Wap. Federation of Educational Assistants, 1988-1991 (Box 23, Folder 40)
  Handwritten notes re autistic children; letter from president of WFEA outlining concerns re bus monitors for special education students, need for training, September 17, 1990; collective bargaining agreement, July 1, 1988 through June 30, 1991
- WFW-Attendance and Leave Policy, 1993 (Box 23, Folder 41)